<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<article>
	<title>Gobby: Installation Guide</title>
	<section><title>Introduction</title>
		<para>This is a brief installation guide for Gobby, the collaborative editor. It is a very preliminary version and you could find updated information on <ulink url="http://gobby.0x539.de/installationguide.html"><literal>http://gobby.0x539.de/installationguide.html</literal></ulink>. Help in crafting good documentation is urgently needed.</para>
	</section>
	<section><title>Microsoft Windows</title>
		<section><title>Binary build</title>
			<para>Gobby's binary build needs at least Windows 2000 to run correctly. You could obtain it on <ulink url="http://gobby.0x539.de/download.html"><literal>http://gobby.0x539.de/download.html</literal></ulink>. Further information could be retrieved from the already mentioned installation guide.</para>
		</section>
		<section><title>Development environment</title>
			<para>It is currently not advised to build a development environment under Microsoft Windows. If you still want to do so please refer to the information in the guide on the wiki.</para>
		</section>
		<section><title>Known limitations</title>
			<para>Gobby does not yet support ZeroConf server autodiscovery on Windows.</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section><title>Linux</title>
		<para>You should look for Gobby in the package list of your favourite version first. However, as major versions are likely to be incompatible you might still be required to install Gobby from source. Please check your distribution manuals how to install the development headers of the required dependencies.</para>
		<para>Gobby may be installed from source just like most other application for Unix-like operating systems. You need to get the tarballs of net6, obby and gobby from <ulink url="http://releases.0x539.de/"><literal>http://darcs.0x539.de/</literal></ulink> first. Then you need to build them in this order by running <literal>./configure, make</literal> and <literal>make install</literal>. Please look at the <literal>README</literal> files of all packages to retrieve the dependency list.</para>
	</section>
	<section><title>Mac OS X</title>
		<para>The only supported method to install Gobby is via <ulink url="http://www.darwinports.org">DarwinPorts (<literal>http://darwinports.org</literal>)</ulink>. Please refer to the installation guide for more information.</para>
	</section>
	<section><title>FreeBSD</title>
		<para>net6, obby and Gobby should compile as is on FreeBSD, but you might need to relocate some pkg-config control files after the installation of the libraries.</para>
<literallayout>
cp /usr/local/lib/pkgconfig/net6-1.1.pc \
  /usr/local/libdata/pkgconfig/
</literallayout>
<literallayout>
cp /usr/local/lib/pkgconfig/obby-0.2.pc \
  /usr/local/libdata/pkgconfig/
</literallayout>
	</section>
</article>
